Finding aid for the Xavier University Center for Adult and Part-Time Students records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Center for Adult and Part-Time Students records
1938-2015
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Center for Adult and Part-Time Students records
1.5 linear feet (3 boxes)
This collection includes minutes, reports, brochures, and other materials stemming from the activity of the Xavier University Center for Adult and Part-Time Students. This entity has had various names throughout its history.
XUA-79
History of Xavier University Center for Adult and Part-time Students
The earliest name for this entity was the Evening College, established in 1841. In 1972 the name changed to the College of Continuing Education. In 1986 the name changed to the Division of Continuing Education and again in 1988 to the Center for Adult and Part-Time Students (CAPS). In 2013 the Center for Adult and Part-Time Students ceased to exist. Its functions were transferred to the Adult, Weekend and Evening Program within the College of Arts and Sciences.
Scope and Content
This collection includes minutes, correspondence, photos, brochures, statistical information and other materials on the activity and programs of the Center for Adult and Part-Time Students.
Statement of Arrangement
Materials in this collection are arranged into series:
Historical Information
Correspondence and Reports
Brochures, Posters, and Announcements
Newspaper Clippings and Releases
Financial Reports and Enrollment Statistics
Course Information
Weekend Degree Program
Photos
Various Topics
Restrictions on Access
Some materials may have restricted access. Please contact the archives staff.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Nontraditional college students--Services for--Ohio; Part-time college students--Services for--Ohio
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Historical Information, 1971-2015
  - Historical Information Center for Part-Time Students / Evening College, 1971-2015 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence and Reports, 1938-1979
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1938-1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1948-1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1959-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Brochures, Posters, and Announcements, 1940-2011
  - Brochures, Posters, and Announcements, 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brochures, Posters, and Announcements, 1971-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Brochures, Posters, and Announcements, 1991-2011 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Newspaper Clippings and Releases, 1938-1966
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1938-1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - News Releases, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Releases and Clippings, 1959-1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Night Side of the News, 1958-1959; undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Financial Reports and Enrollment Statistics, 1950-1961; undated
  - Annual Financial Reports, 1954-1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Enrollment Statistics, 1950-1961; undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Course Information, 1955-1958
  - Certified Professional Secretary Course, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Television College and Courses, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Weekend Degree Program, 1994-1996
  - Weekend Degree Program Marketing Plan, 1995 April (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Weekend Degree Program Brochures, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Photos, 1930-1970
  - Photos, 1930-1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Photos: Business Service Members, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Photos and Correspondence, 1955-1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Various Topics, 1930-2010
  - Search Committee for New Dean, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Employee Relations Dean's List, 1954-1958 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Xavier Chapter of Kappa Sigma Mu, 1940-1948 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Religious and Social Events, 1930-1959 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Marketing Survey of Adult Education in Cincinnati, 1982 November (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Center for Adult and Part-Time Students: Current Status and Recommendations for Future, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 13)